Carlos Martinez



Front End Developer

- ♦ 111 Sherman Place South Orange, NJ 07079
- bwaycarl@gmail.com
- 917-848-8949
- **y** @BwayDev
- BwayCarl
- BroadwayCarl

Skills

- **■** HTML5
- **∃** CSS3
- Js JavaScript
- nede Node.js
- MySQL
- mongoDB
- React

Summary

After 25 successful years in the entertainment industry as a Broadway Local One stagehand specializing in electrics, the sudden coronavirus pandemic has steered me down a different path. While my career is on indefinite hold, I am taking the opportunity to expand my horizons and concentrate on learning the skills needed to jump start a second life in the world of web development.

Having a strong work ethic and being in charge of large crews in conjunction with delegating responsibilities have honed my leadership skills and ingrained in me the importance of teamwork and appreciation of the vast skills needed to form a functioning team unit.

Experience

The Shubert Organization New York, NY

House Electrician, Booth Theatre - September, 2018 - PRESENT House Electrician, Belasco Theatre - August, 2013 - September, 2018

- Responsible for all areas of lighting and electrical power for the entire theater, as well as the power needs for the lighting design, sound design and automation elements of the scenic design of each production.
- In charge of hiring the Electrics Department crew that loads in each attraction (numbers range from 12-30 crew members depending on the production) and the permanent crew that runs and maintains the show during its run.
- Implement initiatives for upgrading the facility's electrical systems to ensure up to date technology and safely replace outdated systems.
- Submit monthly maintenance reports explaining work completed and recommendations for future projects.

Broadway Electrician / Production Electrician New York, NY 1998 - 2013

- Electrician for over 30 Broadway productions including Thoroughly Modern Millie, The Lion King, Aladdin, Farinelli & The King, Hedwig & The Angry Inch, Mary Poppins, The Glass Menagerie, Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?, The River and Freestyle Love Supreme.
- Member of Theatrical Protective Union, Local No. One I.A.T.S.E since 2004.

Education

Rutgers University New Brunswick, NJ

Web Coding Bootcamp - Full Stack Flex - June, 2020 - PRESENT

- Curriculum covering a vast array of computer programming such as HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, jQuery, Node.js, Responsive Design, Heroku, Git, User Authentication, React.js, MySQL, and MongoDB.
- Planned completion of course: December, 2020.

CUNY Queens College, Aaron Copland School of Music Flushing, NY

Music Perfomance Major - Clarinet - September, 1984 - June, 1988